Guide to the William Henry Jackson Photographs, 1869-1874 RL.00625
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Henry Jackson photographs
1869-1878 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jackson, William Henry, 1843-1942
RL.00625
3.2 Linear Feet
William Henry Jackson (1843-1942), was one of the earliest and most important American photographers. From 1869 to 1878 he was official photographer for the U.S. Geological Survey of the Territories. Collection includes 130 photographs and albumen prints, almost all of which Jackson made while employed by the Survey. States represented are Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Utah, and Wyoming. Photographs are organized in several series by year from 1869 to 1874. Other important photographs include both a series and an album of the area now know as Yellowstone National Park; some of Jackson's photographs were shown to Congress prior to their vote to establish it as the first national park.
130 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rubenstein Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William Henry Jackson Photographs were received by the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library as a gift in 1972.
These and other photographs by western expeditionary photographers were purchased from Lowdermilk's bookstore in Washington, D.C. prior to its liquidation.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1843 Apr. 4 Born in Keesville, New York
1858 Began his photography career in New York as a retouching artist
1862-1863 Served in the Union Army
1867 Opened a photography studio in Omaha, Nebraska
1869 Photographed construction along the new Union Pacific Railroad
1869-1878 Photographed the landscape of the Rockies, especially the Yellowstone area and Colorado, for Francis V. Hayden's Geological and Geographic Survey of the Territories
1879 Opened a new studio in Denver, Colorado
1893 Jackson's photographs commissioned by the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad are exhibited at the World's Columbian Exposition
1942 June 30 Died New York, N.Y.
Collection Overview
William Henry Jackson (1843-1942), photographer, artist, and explorer had a long and distinguished career as one of America's earliest and most important photographers, and to this day he has remained one of the best known of the western expeditionary photographers. During the years 1869-1878, Jackson was the official photographer for the U.S. Geological Survey of the Territories conducted by Ferdinand Vandiveer Hayden. This collection includes 130 photographs, albumen prints, almost all of which Jackson made while employed by the Survey. Of these 130 photographs, 68 are unbound, and 62 are bound into an album. The states represented in the collection are Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Utah, and Wyoming. The photographs form a number of series: 1869 Series (3), 1870 Series (20),1871 Series (5), 1872 Series (1), 1873 Series (3), 1874 Series (18), Yellowstone National Park Series (2), Indians Series (11), Not Identified in the Catalogue Series (5), and Album: Photographic Views Of the Yellow Stone National Park Series (62). The photographs of the area now known as Yellowstone National Park may have in part led to the foundation of the of park. A selection of Jackson's photographs were shown to Congress prior to their vote to establish Yellowstone the first National Park.
The series of 1869-1873 are described in: William Henry Jackson, Descriptive Catalogue of the Photographs of the United States Geological Survey of the Territories, for the Years 1869 to 1873, Inclusive, U.S. Geological Survey of the Territories, Miscellaneous Publications, No. 5 (Washington: G.P.O., 1874). The information folders contain copies of the pertinent pages from the Catalogue. The unbound photographs are listed below with abbreviated descriptions. They are arranged first by series and then numerically within each series. The photographs supplied original numbers but not titles, so the Catalogue provided the titles used below. The images for the Series 1869-1872 vary from 4-7 inches x 7-9 inches mounted on 11 x 14 in boards. The images for Series 1873 are approximately 8 or 9 x 13 inches mounted upon 16 x 20 inch boards. The particulars of the unbound and bound photographs from Yellowstone National Park are given with their listings below.
Each photograph bears an original number and title. These titles are listed below within quotation marks. The descriptive catalogue contains fuller descriptions.
Related Material
The following collections in the Duke University David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library may contain related material:
William Bell Photographs, 1872 John K. Hillers Photographs, 1871-1889 and undated Timothy H. O'Sullivan Photographs, 1868-1873
Documentary Photography; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Yellowstone National Park -- Pictorial works; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Photographs; Albumen prints; Photographers; Landscape photography -- West (U.S.); United States -- Discovery and exploration; West (U.S.) -- Discovery and exploration; Jackson, William Henry, 1843-1942; Jackson, William Henry, 1843-1942; Geological Survey (U.S.)
- 1869 Series, 1 box
  Scope and Contents note
  The Union Pacific Railroad, Salt Lake City and Valley, and the Black Hills of Wyoming photographed immediately upon the completion of the road in the summer of 1869.
  - No. 12 Tea-Pot Rock, near Green River Station (Wy.) (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1869-P12)
  - No. 18 View along the Green River (Wy.) (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1869-P18)
  - No. 25 Castle Rocks at the Head of Echo Cañon (Utah) (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1869-P25)
- 1870 Series, 2 boxes
  Views made during August-November, 1870, from Cheyenne, Wyoming, to Colorado City, Colorado, as well as some parts of Utah.
  - No. 52 Castellated Rocks on the Chugwater (Wyoming) (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P52)
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    copy negative available: WHJ-1870-N52
  - No. 54 Band Lands on Laramie River (Wyoming) (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P54)
  - No. 56 Laramie Peak (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P56)
  - No. 62 Camp on the La Bonta (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P62)
  - No. 74 Bad Lands near Caspar Mountain (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P74)
  - No. 75 View from Caspar Mountain (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P75)
  - No. 89 Ridges near Twin Peaks and Valley of the Sweetwater (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P89)
  - No. 92 Along the Summit of Granite Ridge (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P92)
  - No. 93 Along the Summit of Granite Ridge (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P93)
  - No. 100 South Pass City (Wyoming) (Box WHJ1, Print WHJ-1870-P100)
  - No. 101 Beaver Dam Gulch (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P101)
  - No. 102 Wind River Mountains and Fremont's Peak (Wyoming) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P102)
  - No. 125 Unitah Mountains (Utah) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P125)
  - No. 129 El Capitan in Miniature (Utah) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P129)
  - No. 137 A Natural Cave near Green River (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P137)
  - No. 138 A Perpendicular Bluff (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P138)
  - No. 142 Bluff of Quartzite near Mouth of Red Creek (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P142)
  - No. 144 Coal-bearing Bluffs near Point of Rocks, on Bitter Creek, Union Pacific R.R. (Wyoming) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P144)
  - No. 151 Platte Cañon (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P151)
  - No. 153 Pleasant Park (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1870-P153)
- 1871 Series, 1 box
  From Ogden, Utah, via Fort Hall, Idaho, to Fort Ellis Montana then up the Yellowstone River to the lake, to the headwaters of the Madison.
  - No. 184 Mount Garfield (Idaho) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1871-P184)
  - No. 197 Mystic Lake (Montana) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1871-P197)
  - No. 201 Valley of the Yellowstone (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1871-P201)
  - No. 279 Yellowstone Lake (Wyoming) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1871-P279)
  - No. 308 Point of Rocks, Beaver Head River (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1871-P308)
- 1872 Series, 1 box
  - No. 415 View in the Teton Range (Idaho) (Box WHJ2, Print WHJ-1872-P415)
- 1873 Series, 1 box
  These three photographs, the largest ones in the collection, do not provide titles except for a caption on one of them. They do contain numbers and the Catalogue provided the following descriptions. Jackson made this series in Colorado. These three photographs once formed parts of panoramas.
  - No. 66-2 A Wilderness of Snow Streaked Mountain Summits (Box WHJ/AG1 (Box 6 of 7), Print WHJ-1873-P1)
    copy negative available: WHJ-1873-N1
  - No. 67-3 Very Nearly Due North Looking Down on the Spur of Mount McClellan and Directly Opposite from Gray's peak (Box WHJ/AG1 (Box 6 of 7), Print WHJ-1873-P2)
    General note
    The following two photographs formed part of the panorama: "Nos. 65-70 A panoramic view of the Front Range of the Rocky Mountains from near Gray's and Torrey's Peaks, 360° in Six Views, 150 Miles in Diameter."
    copy negative available: WHJ-1873-N2
  - Nos. 102-104 A Panoramic View of the Elk Mountains: No. 102 "White Rock Mtn." White Rock Looking West from a Long Spur of Sharp Dividing Crest Which Separates Two Amphitheaters, One on the Right Debouching into East River on the North, and the Other (Box WHJ/AG1 (Box 6 of 7), Print WHJ-1873-P3)
- 1874 Series, 2 boxes
  Jackson also made this series in Colorado. It is listed in: William Henry Jackson, Descriptive Catalogue of the Photographs of the United States Geological Survey of the Territories, For the Years 1869-1875, Inclusive, 2nd ed., U.S. Geological and Geographical Survey of the Territories, Miscellaneous Publications, No. 5 (Washington: G.P.O., 1875). The geographical location of the scenes is described as: "Colorado. Middle Park, via Berthound Pass; thence to San Juan mining-region, via the Blue River, Hoosier Pass, and the Rio Grande, including all points of interest in Antelope and Boker's Park, and about the head of San Miguel. The La Platta Mountains and the remarkable prehistoric ruins in the cañon of the Mancos and about El Late, taking in finally, on the way back, the Monument Rocks, between Colorado City and Denver." The photographs were made from 5 x 8 inch negatives.
  - "No. 67 Grand Lake" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P67)
  - "No. 68 Fisherman's Cabin on Grand Lake" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P68)
  - "No. 73 Falls at Foot of Round Top Mtn." (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P73)
  - "No. 79 Middle Park. East from Mt. Bross" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P79)
  - "No. 83 Middle Park. View up the Blue from the Grand" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P83)
  - "No. 84 Looking North from the Mouth of the Blue. Middle Park" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P84)
  - "No. 92 Blue River Mtns. South from Near Ute Peak" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P92)
  - "No. 98 Pleasant Park. View South" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P98)
  - "No. 99 Pleasant Park. Profile Rock" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P99)
  - "No. 115 Monument Park" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P115)
  - "No. 127 Lake Under Bristol Head. Antelope Park. Lake Santa Maria" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P127)
    copy negative available: WHJ-1874-N127
  - "No. 132 View on the Rio Grand Near Lost-T Rail Creek" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P132)
  - "No. 141 West from Sultan Mtn" (Box WHJ3, Print WHJ-1874-P141)
  - "No. 157 Ancient Ruins in the Cañon of the Mancos" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-1874-P157)
    copy negative available: WHJ-1874-N157
  - "No. 158 Ancient Ruins in the Cañon of the Mancos" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-1874-P158)
  - "No. 161 Ruined City at Aztec Springs. The Outer Wall" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-1874-P161)
  - "No. 168 Old Tower Near the McElmo" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-1874-P168)
  - "No. 169 Ruined Fortress on the Hovenweep" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-1874-P169)
- Not Identified in the Catalogue Series, circa 1875, 1 box
  These numbered, but uncaptioned, photographs are all identified by printed labeling as belonging to the Survey, but they do not appear in the Catalogue. However, the numbering of the photographs in each series in the Catalogue has many gaps. At least two series, perhaps three, are probably represented, since there are two different styles of printed labeling and there are two number 57s. Presumably, these photographs date from the later years of the Survey, those after 1875 not listed in the Catalogue. The size and printed format of the first four photographs are identical to those in the series 1869-1872, but the printed format of No. 843 is unique to the collection. The supplied descriptions below take the place of original or Catalogue titles.
  - No. 35 Meadow before Boulder-strewn Mountain (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Unidentified-P35)
  - No. 57 View of Valley with Two Men and Mountains (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Unidentified-P57)
  - No. 57 Layered Cliff and Rocky Landscape (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Unidentified-P57a)
  - No. 234 Railroad through Rocky Cut (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Unidentified-P234)
  - No. 843 Stratified Bluff, Cave, and Men. (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Unidentified-P843)
- Yellowstone National Park Series, undated, 1 box
  These two albumen prints provide titles but not the name of the photographer. Comparison with negatives housed at the National Archives provided the attribution for these photographs. The images are 13 ¼ x 10 inches mounted on 14 x 11 mat boards. The mat boards are gilt-edged. These photographs are identical in size and mounting to five photographs attributed to John K. Hillers. See his California Series.
  - "Little Fire Hole Falls" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Yellowstone-PA)
    copy negative available: WHJ-Yellowstone-NA
  - "Keppler's Cascade" (Box WHJ4, Print WHJ-Yellowstone-PB)
- Indian Series, 1869-1878, 1 box
  There are eleven photographs of Indians, portraits of either individuals or groups of two or more persons. All eleven have the name of the U.S. Geological Survey of the Territories printed on them which dates them between 1869 and 1878. Nine of the photographs have Jackson's name printed on them. There are two printing styles, one style for Nos. 4 and 20 and another for all the others. The prints are mounted on 11 x 14 inch boards. Nos. 102 and 335 have rectangular images. The other nine images were all done with oval masks. Nos. 797 and 798 are two oval images on the same print. The principal list of the Indian photographs is William Henry Jackson, Descriptive Catalogue of Photographs of North American Indians, U.S. Geological Survey of the Territories, Miscellaneous Publications, No. 9 (Washington: G.P.O., 1877) This Catalogue superseded the Catalogue of Photographs of Indians, from Negatives in the Possession of the United States Geological Survey, Collected from various sources, and Covering a Period of Twenty-Five Years, 1874, published as a second edition of the 1874 Catalogue cited earlier. Jackson authored both catalogues, but they listed not only his photographs but those of other photographers as well. There is some question about whether or not Jackson made the eleven Indian photographs in this collection, including those with printed labels "W.H. Jackson Photo.," or merely was in charge of their cataloging and issuance. The catalogues list photographs of Indians made by various photographers and in the possession of the Survey. Although the 1877 Catalogue was designed to replace the 1874 Catalogue, both must be used when identifying the photographs, including those in this collection. Several of the photographs listed below were omitted from the 1877 Catalogue but appear in the 1874 Catalogue. There are other problems that suggest caution in the use of the catalogs. Photograph No. 335 was not listed in either edition. No. 248 has two different listings in the 1874 and only one in the 1877. The listings in the 1874 are not entirely in numerical order, and No. 516 was found on the last page. Since the photographs are numbered, but not captioned, errors in identification can easily occur. The titles in the list below are from the 1877 Catalogue, from the 1874 Catalogue when unavailable in the 1877, and supplied when not listed in either source. In several instances, the description for each item provides detailed information concerning the source of the title.
  - No. 4 Apaches. Santo (Side). Coyotero (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P4)
  - No. 20 Pueblos. Group of Corridores. Young men who are selected to run foot races during the "feasts" or religious (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P20)
  - No. 102 Creeks. Group of the Preceding Chiefs. Lo-Cha-Ha-Jo, the Drunken Terrapin; Tal-Wa-Mi-Ko, Town King; Tam-Si-Pel-Man, Thompson Perryman; and Ho-Tul-Ko-Mi-Ko, Chief of the Whirlwind. (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P102)
    copy negative available: WHJ-Indians-N102
  - No. 199 Dakotas or Sioux. Medicine Bottle. Son of Little Crow. Mdewakanton (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P199)
  - No. 248 Dakotas or Sioux. Young Brave. Santee (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P248)
  - No. 335 Unidentified. Older Man, Seated. Elaborately Dressed. This number was omitted from the Catalogue in both 1874 and 1877, but No. 335 falls among a series of of numbers assigned to photographs of Dakotas to which it may belong (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P335)
  - No. 508 Osage, Missouri. A Chief. Omitted from 1877 Catalogue but listed in 1874 Catalogue (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P508)
  - No. 516 Miscellaneous. Group of Occowas from British Guiana. Listed in 1874 Catalogue, but omitted from 1877 Catalogue. (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P516)
  - No. 627 Pueblos. Young Girls and Women of the Pueblo of Taos (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P627)
  - No. 729 Tonkaway. Skull of Medicine Man. Listed in 1874 Catalogue, but omitted from 1877 Catalogue. (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P729)
  - No. 797 and 798 (Two portraits on one plate) Utes, Utah and Colorado. Various Braves. Listed in 1874 Catalogue. Nos. 797 and 798 in 1877 Catalogue are front and profile views of Bloody Mouth, a Dakota. However, both portraits here are front views, and are apparently not Bloody Mouth. (Box WHJ5, Print WHJ-Indians-P797 and 798)
- Album: Photographic Views Of the Yellow Stone National Park Series, 1871-1872, 1 box
  This album (14 x 12 inches) contains 62 photographs taken by Jackson in Yellowstone National Park during 1871-1872. The title of the album is tooled in gold on the spine of the volume. There is no other identification on the volume. Printing on the mat boards identifies Jackson as the photographer. The prints were made and mounted between 1872, the date of the last pictures and the year when Yellowstone became a national park, and 1879 when Jackson moved from Washington D.C., to Denver Colorado. The printing on the boards of many of the photographs identified Jackson as a photographer in Washington. The album contains 52 photographs from 1871 and 10 from 1872. The printing on the boards identifies the 1871 photographs as belonging to two photographic series: Yellowstone Series and Hot Spring Series. These series, designated by the photographer, were not used in the organization of the collection, but are provided as part of the title for each image. The following list itemizes all 62 photographs. They are listed in the order of their appearance in the album. More detailed descriptions are in the Descriptive Catalogue of the Photographs of the United States Geological Survey of the Territories, for the Years 1869 to 1873, Inclusive (Washington G.P.O., 1874) the information folder contains copies of the pertinent pages. Quotation marks around the title indicate that the title was taken from the photograph rather than from the Catalogue or other source
  - "200 or 201 Valley of the Yellowstone, Below Boettlers, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P1)
  - "202 Exit of the Yellowstone, from the Mountains, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P2)
  - "204 Camp at Boettlers, Emigrant Peak, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P3)
  - "205 Yellowstone River, above Boettlers, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P4)
  - "206 The Lower Cañon, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P5)
  - "209 Cinnabar Mountain, from Below, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P6)
  - "212 Devils Slide, Cinnabar Mountain, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P7)
  - "213 Devils Slide, Cinnabar Mountain, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P8)
  - "215 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, Hot Water Fissures, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P9)
  - "217 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, Upper Basin, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P10)
    copy negative available: WHJ.Album.N10
  - "218 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, The Great Spring, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P11)
  - "229 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, from Above Looking Down, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P12)
  - "230 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, from Above Looking Down, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P13)
  - 450 Group of Lower Basins, on the Main Terrace, Mammoth Hot Springs, 1872 Series (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P14)
  - 455 Groups of Small Flowing Springs, and Sulphur Vents, Back of the Great Central Hot Spring, Mammoth Hot Springs, 1872 Series (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P15)
  - "224 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, Hot Water Fissures, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P16)
    copy negative available: WHJ.Album.N16
  - "226 Hot Springs on Gardiners River, The Cap of Liberty, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P17)
  - 227 Cap of Liberty, Near View. Lacks printed caption of Hot Spring Series, 1871 Series (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P18)
  - "233 Tower Falls, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P19)
    copy negative available: WHJ.Album.N19
  - "234 Tower Falls, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P20)
  - "236 Tower Creek, above the Falls, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P21)
  - "238 Column Rocks, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P22)
  - "239 Lower Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P23)
  - "241 Lower Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P24)
    copy negative available: WHJ.Album.N24
  - "242 Lower Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P25)
  - "243 Lower Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P26)
  - "244 Upper Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P27)
  - "245 Upper Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P28)
  - "[247] Upper Falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P29)
  - "[248, 249, 250, or 251] Grand Cañon of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P30)
  - "253 Grand Cañon of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P31)
    copy negative available: WHJ.Album.N31
  - "255 Crystal Falls, on Cascade Creek, between the Upper and Lower Falls, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P32)
  - "257 Yellowstone River, above the Falls, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P33)
  - "258 Yellowstone River, above the Falls, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P34)
  - "260 Boiling Spring at Sulphur Mountain, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P35)
  - "263 Crater of the Mud Geyser, on the Yellowstone, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P36)
  - "264 Mud Geyser, on the Yellowstone River, Hot Spring Series" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P37)
  - "267 Yellowstone Lake, Where the River Leaves it, Yellowstone Series 1871" (Box WHJ7, Print WHJ.Album.P38)